Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ben-thornton-486b781 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

HR Transformation
Change Management
Organizational Design

Languages

English

Ben Thornton

Partner at PwC, helping HR leaders to have light bulb moments connecting people & technology to make lives better.

Greater Brighton and Hove Area

Summary

I believe that people are at the heart of business success. This drives my passion for what makes business successful and to support leaders on doing the right things for success. In an age of digital disruption HR has consequently never had a bigger role.

I help HR leaders to think through, justify and deploy creative solutions to these challenges. I can resourcefully drive change programmes to deliver business results by transforming key people processes, operating models and technologies.

Operating at Board level I bring my experiences of successfully managing `difficult change environments where cultural or behaviour change is essential. I am a veteran of over 15 enterprise application deployments including SuccessFactors, Workday and Oracle.

I am very fortunate to spend my days (and some nights) having conversations with interesting people on topics they feel strongly about. I am inspired by open and honest conversations and have been fortunate to develop deep relationships with the leaders and their teams on whose transformation journeys I have been fortunate to be part of.

I love connecting people and facilitating "aha" moments that come from working with passionate people who care about making their functions and businesses better places to work.

Common Misspellings: Ben Thorton James Thornton Ben Thompson Neb Thornton

Specialties: HR Transformation, technology enabled HR Transformation, HR Technology, HR SaaS, SuccessFactors, HR Capability Development, HR Service Delivery Models, HR Shared

Services, Lean Servicing, Organisation Design, Leaning Services, Recruitment Process Outsourcing, Payroll Transformation, Business Case development, Case for change, Sourcing Advisory, outsourcing evaluation.

Experience

PwC

11 years 4 months

Partner

July 2018 - Present (5 years 6 months)

London, United Kingdom

Director

September 2012 - June 2018 (5 years 10 months)

London, England Metropolitan Area

I help clients achieve me through the people they employee which often means focusing on the people processes and the outputs of HR.

Atos Consulting

Associate Partner

May 2008 - August 2012 (4 years 4 months)

I work with clients to help them address the people aspects of business transformations. My particular specialism is Human Resources and I am intrigued to learn about the different ways that HR functions assist their business to align people to execution.

Aon

4 years 11 months

Exec Director, HR Shared Services, EMEA August 2007 - April 2008 (9 months)

I was responsible for the scoping and feasibility phase of an EMEA wide HR Transformation and HR Shared Services project across EMEA.

Executive Director

June 2003 - August 2007 (4 years 3 months)

Lead the definition of the diversification strategy for Aon Consulting through the articulation of a non Employee Benefits product and services roadmap. Lead the integration of WfF and then lead the HR Services Division with a dstrong focus on business development.

Water for Fish Managing Director 2005 - 2007 (2 years)

Lead the WfF business and its integration into Aon whilst deliverying its annual business plan.

Aon Consulting HR Solutions Managing Director 2003 - 2007 (4 years)

I lead the development of the non Employee Benefits Division of Aon Consulting. There was a strong focus on business development and we successfuly grew the business organically and through acquisition which saw the purchase of WfF and its rapid integration into Aon.

Aon Limited
Director of HR Direct
1999 - 2003 (4 years)

Lead the transformation of the UK HR function and the implmentation of a new business partner model. Established, expanded and then consolidated the HR Shared Services Centre for the UK business which at its peak looked after 20,000 employees, processed 70,000+ transactions paying out £350m pa.

Deloitte Consulting

Manager

September 1995 - September 1998 (3 years 1 month)

Run a number of HR Consulting assignments including 12 ERP implemntations.

Bain Hogg

Manager

September 1990 - September 1995 (5 years 1 month)

Lead a HR team providing a full operational HR service to the London operations. Lead the HR M&A team focusing on pre and post deal HR/ workforce issues.

Eastern Electricty Personnel Officer 1988 - 1991 (3 years) Operation HR position providing generalist HR support to al HQ functions. Speaclialist placements in Industry Relations, Learning & Development and HRIS.

Education

University of Warwick - Warwick Business School MBA, Business Administration and Management, General · (1994 - 1995)

Lancaster University Ili, Socilogy · (1985 - 1988)